JANE DOE
（无名氏）
I always had to do this alone.
一直都是我一个人处理这样的事情
But the three of you joined me today.
今天有你们三个人陪着我
-Thank you for coming. -There's no need to thank us.
-谢谢你们能过来 -不用客气
But seeing how we couldn't even put a name to these victims
但看到无法探明这些受害者尸体身份
makes me sad.
我感到伤心
So people don't come here.
所以也没有人到这里来
Thank you for coming today.
谢谢你们能来
These victims faced a bitter end after a life of hard work.
这些受害者忙碌了一生 到最后结局竟这么悲惨
Please help them, so they could be happy over there.
请帮助他们吧 让他们可以在天国安乐
And give Gu Young-chun a taste of his own medicine.
让具永春尝一尝地狱的滋味
To someone like Gu Young-chun, that's too generous of a punishment.
地狱对他来说都是一种奢侈
I heard that
我听说
Captain Yoon has been tirelessly working to find the victims' families.
尹组长一直在忙着找受害者的家属
I didn't think she'd come here.
我没想到她会来这里
Captain Yoon
尹组长
isn't cutting her hair for the victims.
为了受害者一直没剪头发
Why her hair?
为什么？
She thinks the inconvenience of having long hair
她要用留长发带来的不便
is what she can do to mourn.
来悼念亡者
I guess having this sense of guilt…
我们这行总是避免不了
comes with our job.
心里某个角落产生的负罪感
Learning from the unprecedented case
在得知这个造成重大伤亡的
which resulted in countless victims,
前所未有的案件后
we see the need to set up
政府认为有必要采取
a comprehensive, government-wide solution for the public safety.
全面的对策 以保护人民的安全
To prevent from making the same mistake in the future,
为防止未来发生相同的失误
we will put together an investigation manual
我们将基于具永春的案件
based on Gu Young-chun's case.
编制调查手册
We are setting up the structure, so everyone can be informed.
我们正在为所有警察都能 处理这类案件而努力
Moreover,
此外
police officers who committed grave mistakes
在调查连环杀人犯具永春的过程中
while investigating the serial killer, Gu Young-chun,
有重大过失的警察
were reprimanded to a great extent.
已经受到了严厉的责罚
With this momentum,
以此为契机
we'll solve the unsolved cases of violent crimes by this year.
我们将在今年内侦破未结的暴力案件
And we will do our best
我们将会尽全力
to keep our people safe.
保障人民的安全
Good luck.
祝你好运
As you all know, we'll be studying Gu Young-chun's case.
大家都知道 我们要研究的案例是不久前被逮捕的
The serial killer we recently apprehended.
连环杀人案的凶手具永春的案件
The public and the higher-ups are criticizing us
公众和高层都在批评我们
that we didn't catch the killer soon enough.
说我们没有及时抓住杀人犯
It's not like we're not trying.
我们又不是故意不抓他
That's right.
没错
He hid and didn't leave any evidence.
他计划好了躲起来而且没有任何证据
-What were we supposed to do with him? -I know that it's a hassle.
-我们能拿他怎么办呢？ -我就知道这个案子很麻烦
But we've never had someone like Gu Young-chun.
我们从没有遇到过具永春这样的罪犯
If we'd caught Gu Young-chun sooner,
如果我们早一点抓住具永春
we wouldn't have this many victims.
就不会有那么多受害者了
Was there a problem with the initial investigation?
初步调查出了什么问题吗？
There was.
有一个问题
The incidents took place in different areas.
因为犯罪发生在不同的地区
The investigations were done by different stations.
调查是由不同的警局进行的
And putting together the information took a long time.
光是将线索整合在一起 就花了很长时间
If we were to reorganize the protocol,
如果改变一下流程
so we can investigate initially,
让我们进行初步调查
we might be able to lessen the confusion.
也许可以减少一些混乱
Great. What else?
非常好 还有其他意见吗？
After Gu Young-chun killed the wealthy elderly,
具永春杀了富有的老人后
he changed his MO.
改变了作案方式
Despite receiving multiple missing persons reports on our victims,
尽管我们收到了 许多女性受害者的失踪报告
they were categorized as simple runaway cases.
但都被简单地归类为离家出走案件
It's not possible to file adults missing in our system.
关于成年人失踪的报案本来就不成立
There were 11 missing women.
失踪的女性有11名
The fact that they were excluded from our investigation is a problem.
但是我们的调查却将她们排除在外 这是有问题的
And we should recognize that
我们必须承认
our existing investigation method didn't work.
我们以前的调查方法行不通
Questioning the victim's acquaintances and ex-convicts
审问受害者的社会关系和有前科的人
is the first step of our investigation.
是我们调查的第一步
How could we ignore that?
我们怎么能跳过这一步
I'm not saying we should ignore it.
我并没有说要跳过这一步
Gu Young-chun's case.
在具永春一案中
It was confirmed he had no motives.
经证实 他是没有作案动机的
It's a crime we've never experienced.
这种犯罪是我们从未遇到过的
Therefore, we need to accept new investigation methods.
因此我们必须接受新的调查方法
She has a point. I agree with her.
有道理 我同意她的观点
The report from the Analysis Team was spot on once again.
犯罪行为分析组的报告非常准确
However, it would be prudent for us
但是我们也要考虑到
to also discuss the risk of only relying
仅仅依赖犯罪行为分析报告
on the behavioral analysis reports.
带来的风险
Here's the most ironic factor of this case.
这个案件最讽刺的是
It was figuring out the murder weapon.
作案的工具是
A hexagon-shaped steel hammer.
一个六边形钢锤
Why hadn't we thought of that?
我们怎么没有想到？
No one uses a steel hammer to kill people.
没有人会用钢锤杀人
That's why.
这就是原因
Gu Young-chun chose the steel hammer
具永春用钢锤
to take down the victims easily.
可以将受害者轻松打倒
In other words, killing was his sole goal.
也就是说 杀人是他的唯一目的
By controlling his victims, he showed off his power.
通过控制受害者 他实现了炫耀武力的目的
And he prepared for his killings.
而且他还为杀戮作了充足准备
-"Prepared"? -I mentioned it earlier.
-充足准备？ -我之前说过
He improved a hammer so the job would be easier.
他改进了钢锤 好让他更好压制受害者
He took a full-body X-ray to study where the body should be severed.
为了研究如何切割身体 研究了全身X光照片
Once he started killing,
他开始杀戮后
the degree of desecration gradually escalated.
逐渐加大了对尸体的破坏程度
So the preparations
因此准备作案的过程
and the act of desecration gave him the thrill.
和毁尸灭迹的过程给他带来了快感
Correct.
正确
So he's not the delusional type who experiences hallucinations,
看得出来他并没有幻想症
but I'm not sure if he had a sense of mission.
但是我不确定他是否怀着某种使命
I'd say he does exhibit the traits.
我觉得他没有表现出这种特征
He did say he committed the murders to root out social evils.
他确实说过他作案 是为了扫除社会上的罪恶
Using such preposterous logic,
他想用这种荒唐的逻辑
he tried to justify what he did.
为自己的行为开脱
Power, influence, and money.
权力 影响力和金钱
This world where the wealthy get rich illegally,
这个世界 富人为非作歹大发横财
women live promiscuously,
女人不知自爱
and civil servants live like bugs.
而公务员如同蛀虫
They all have to be punished!
他们都要受到惩罚！
Gu Young-chun.
具永春
He could go on about his "sense of mission."
他可以继续鼓吹他所谓的使命感
But essentially, he purposely chose weak targets
但是实际上他专挑
whom he could take down easily.
可以轻易制服的弱者下手
He's just
他只是一个
a cowardly loser who's all talk.
只会说大话的卑鄙胆小鬼
I'll build a factory right here.
我要在这里建一座工厂
-Hey! -Look!
-嘿 -看啊
Ta-da!
快看
-Look, right here. -Ye-won, Yu-hwa.
-看 就在这里 -叶文 玉华
It's time to go home. Come on.
该回家了 快点
-Okay!
-好的
Ji-hwan, let's go home and eat.
吉黄 吃饭了
Okay, Mom!
好的 妈妈
Jun, let's go home.
骏 我们回家吧
-Okay. -What are you doing there alone?
-好的 -你一个人在这干什么？
Come on.
快点
Don't people like me all have the same story?
我这样的人 不是很明显吗？
An abusive father.
父亲暴力
And a miserable childhood with no one to lean on.
童年凄惨 无依无靠
So do you blame your father?
你认为都是因为你父亲吗？
You've never lived with a father
喝醉酒就拿着锤子威胁家人
who threatens you with a hammer every time he gets drunk, right?
你没和这种父亲生活过吧？
I never lived with my father.
我没和父亲生活过
He passed away the day I was born.
我出生那天 他去世了
You're lucky.
你真走运
It's better to not have one than to grow up with a father like that.
我那种父亲 不如没有
No wonder I'm like this.
我注定了会走上邪路
You think that's the reason?
你觉得这是原因所在？
I thought you were a criminal behavioral analyst.
你不是犯罪行为分析师吗
Didn't you hear such a childhood could cause you to become a serial killer?
你不知道这样的童年经历 会催生出连环杀人犯吗？
A cowardly way to justify himself.
卑鄙地让自己的罪行合理化
I'm home.
我回来了
You're late.
这么晚
You're still up?
您还没睡啊？
-Good night. -You too.
-晚安
Come in.
请进
-You're still up? -Yes.
-您还没睡吗？ -是啊
-Here, have some. -Thanks.
-来 吃点这个吧 -谢谢
I guess I'm getting old. I tossed and turned a little,
我想我可能已经老了 我在床上翻来覆去
and I can't fall asleep anymore.
就是睡不着
I made it today. It turned out nicely. Try it.
这是我今天做的 还不错 尝一下吧
Okay, thank you. Try to get some sleep.
好的 谢谢 去睡一会吧
What's with the booze?
这酒是从哪来的？
He can't even drink.
他不喝酒的啊
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
You see, we never
你看 我们从来
agree to interview requests,
不接受采访
but he kept pestering us about it.
但是他一直缠着我们
I didn't know Woo-ju had such a cool friend.
我不知道宇宙有这样一个优秀的朋友
What a pretty name. Reporter Choi Yoon-ji.
多美的名字啊 崔润智记者
Here, have some coffee.
来 喝点咖啡吧
-Thank you. -How nice is this?
-谢谢 -真不错啊
Thanks to Reporter Choi,
托崔记者的福
we can sit down and enjoy coffee in the office.
我们才有机会坐在办公室里喝咖啡
Cheers.
干杯
-Cheers.
-干杯
-It's good. -It is.
-好喝 -是的
As I mentioned last time…
我上次说过
No pictures, please.
不能拍照
Oh, this.
哦 这个啊
It's like a soldier's weapon on the battlefield.
它就像士兵在战场的武器一样
I always have it with me wherever I go.
不管拍不拍照 走到哪我都带着它
I won't be taking any pictures today.
我今天不会拍照
It'll just be a story that introduces the team.
我只想写一篇介绍工作团队的报道
My gosh, why am I nervous?
天啊 我怎么有点紧张啊
I feel like I'm being interrogated.
这感觉就像在受审一样
Relax. It'll be like a chat.
放松点 只是随便聊聊
Okay, sounds good.
好的 这样挺好
Here's what I was most curious about.
这是我最好奇的问题
Common motives for murder
通常谋杀的动机
include money, lust, hatred,
包括金钱 情感 仇恨
and revenge, right?
复仇 对吗？
That's right.
是的
However, Gu Young-chun
但是具永春
is a serial murderer who completely deviates from that.
是一个和以上情况 完全不符合的连环杀人犯
What do you think is the reason behind
你认为这种没有动机的杀人犯
such motiveless murders?
犯罪的原因是什么？
Here's what I think.
我想谈谈我的看法
Feelings of social isolation
越来越多的人感受到
have been on the rise,
社会的割裂
and these brutal crimes
这种残暴的犯罪是由
are manifestations of blind hatred resulting from that.
盲目的仇恨所引发的
-Blind hatred? -Yes.
-盲目的仇恨？ -是的
Profilers aren't psychics.
犯罪侧写师不是通灵之人
We analyze the psychological and behavioral patterns of culprits
我们分析罪犯的心理和行为类型
and assist in investigations so they can be caught quickly.
并协助调查 这样才可以迅速将他们逮捕
We use accumulated data to analyze such patterns.
我们使用积累的数据分析这些类型
Interviewing other convicts is a part of that.
对其他罪犯的采访也是数据的一部分
There are always traces left at crime scenes.
犯罪现场总会留下痕迹
And every murderer leaves a trail. Their behaviors
每个杀人犯都留下了痕迹 他们的行为
show us what their motives are and what they're trying to achieve.
显示了他们的动机和目的
That's right. Forensics
没错 鉴定组
finds evidence at the scenes.
负责在现场寻找证据
Profilers analyze the clues and circumstantial evidence
犯罪侧写师负责根据对现场的观察
based on our observations of the scenes.
分析线索和间接证据
We're analyzing the Southwest Case at the moment.
我们正在分析西南部案件
I want to say this to the culprit who will probably read this.
我想告诉可能会读到这篇文章的罪犯
"We'll catch you soon."
我们很快会抓住你
I hope so too.
我也希望如此
I can tell you this one thing for sure.
我可以肯定地告诉你
Perfect crime doesn't exist.
这世上并不存在完美的犯罪
Way to go, Yoon-ji.
加把劲 润智
I always knew that you were so capable.
我一直都知道你很能干的
I'm so proud of you.
我为你感到骄傲
This article will be a hit.
这篇文章会引起轰动的
I need to focus.
我需要集中精神
Oh, right. Sorry.
好的 对不起
You know how important this article is.
你也知道这篇文章有多么重要
Fix this typo, Yoon-ji.
你打错字了 润智
The Behavioral Analysis Team will become the stepping stone
犯罪行为分析组将会
of the 21st century police investigations reform.
引领21世纪警察调查改革
Inspector Song Ha-young?
宋霞永警卫？
He's not here. You called the Special Crime Squad.
他不是这边的 这是机搜队
Hello?
你好
May I speak to Inspector Song?
我找宋警卫
-Who? -Inspector Song Ha-young.
-找谁？ -宋霞永警卫
Call the Analysis Team.
请致电犯罪行为分析组
"The Behavioral Analysis Team will become the stepping stone
犯罪行为分析组将会
of the 21st century police investigations reform."
引领21世纪警察调查改革
He's not here at the moment. Okay.
他不在 好的
Goodness gracious.
老天啊
I keep getting calls from people I don't even know.
我不断接到陌生人的电话
I didn't know it'd go viral like this.
我没想到这篇文章流传这么广
I didn't know so many people would read Yoon-ji's article.
我也没想到这么多人会看润智的文章
The media has such a wide reach.
这家媒体的影响力真大
Maybe it's all thanks to our team.
也许是我们分析组的影响力大
He has stepped out of the office.
他出门了
I'm afraid I can't give you his number.
不好意思 我不能给你他的电话号码
Okay.
好的
This will go on for a while.
这种情况还要持续一阵子了
BEHAVIORAL ANALYSIS TEAM STEPPING STONE FOR INVESTIGATIONS REFORM
（犯罪行为分析组引领调查改革）
REPORTER CHOI YOON-JI, FACT TODAY
（《今日真相》记者崔润智）
Choi Yoon-ji is smart.
崔润智真聪明
HOW THE PROFILER CAUGHT GU YOUNG-CHUN
（犯罪侧写师如何抓住具永春？）
IT'S THAT CAREER YOU SAW IN THE SILENCE OF THE LAMBS
（电影《沉默的羔羊》中的职业）
I don't even want to see Ha-young.
我不想见宋霞永
Do you have to do this?
这对被降职的我是不是太过分了？
Stop bothering me already.
不要烦我了
PHOTO OF SONG HA-YOUNG
（宋霞永的照片）
HOW THE PROFILER CAUGHT GU YOUNG-CHUN
（犯罪侧写师如何抓住具永春？）
Hey, you're early.
嘿 早啊
What's that?
这是什么？
INSPECTOR SONG HA-YOUNG CRIMINAL PROFILER
（宋霞永警卫 犯罪侧写师）
Im Moo-sik, this scumbag.
林武植这个混蛋
We clearly said no photos.
我们明确说了不要登照片
It's for the better.
这样更好
I'm glad the media is interested.
我很高兴媒体很感兴趣
We've been talking about expanding Forensics
我们正在讨论将鉴定组
into Scientific Investigations Division.
扩大为科学调查股
I'm guessing the higher-ups are starting to understand our language.
我想高层开始明白我们的话了
We were heavily beaten.
我们被打惨了
With that being said, I want Scientific Investigations
说到这 我希望科学调查股
to be led by you, Captain Kook.
由你来带领 国组长
-Me? -Yes.
-我吗？ -是的
What are you talking about? My team keeps me busy enough.
说什么呀？我自己那组都够让我忙了
I'm trying to convince them,
我正在说服高层
so don't just say no, and give it a thought first.
不要急着回绝我 先仔细考虑一下
There is nothing to think about.
没有什么好考虑的
I don't need that position. All I need is my team.
我不需要那个职位 我只想领导我那个组
On top of that, we only have three people.
再说了 我们组只有三个人
It's not an expansion if I'm gone.
如果我走了 这不是扩大编制
-It's a reduction. -Goodness.
-而是减少编制了 -天啊
What do you think?
你有什么想法？
Yes, you can do it instead.
要不你来担任这个职位吧
I'll do whatever Captain Kook decides.
我会服从国组长的决定
But I agree he should lead Scientific Investigations.
但是我赞成他担任科学调查股的组长
-See? I told you. -Even he thinks that.
-听到了吗？我告诉过你 -他也是这么认为的
I have enough.
我受够了
-Stop. -Hey,
-等等 -喂
-Detective Nam. What is it? -Forget that.
-我是南刑警 什么事啊？ -算了吧
-Gocheong-dong? -Deal with Moo-sik.
-高清洞？ -和林武植打交道
-That's Guro-gu. -All right.
-在九老区啊 -好的
-Why alone? What about Yoon? -He never listens.
-为什么一个人？尹组长呢？ -他从不听我们的话
She's at the prosecution? Okay. You should go.
她在检察厅？好的 你去吧
Wait, one second.
等一下
Analysis Team should go with him.
分析组和他一起去吧
-Go where? -Gocheong-dong.
-去哪里？ -高清洞
I'll send them over. Okay.
他们马上来 好的
Why?
为什么呀？
It's related to the Southwest Case.
这个事情和西南部案件有关
GOCHEONG-DONG, GURO-GU
（高清洞 九老区）
-Is this it? -Yes.
-到了吗？ -是的
The end of April.
案发时间是四月底
The weapon was a kitchen knife.
作案工具是一把厨房用刀
The victim was murdered around 2:30 a.m. in front of the door,
受害者约在上午2点半在家门口被杀
also with the key in the keyhole.
锁上还插着钥匙
-Aren't you coming in? -We start from the outside.
-你不进屋吗？ -我们先在外面看看
We have to check the environment and the structure of the building.
我们需要查看一下环境和建筑的结构
That way, we can infer the reason why the killer chose this place.
这样 我们可以推断杀人犯 选择这个地方的原因
We think like the culprit and try to guess their movement.
我们要从罪犯的角度 猜测他们的行为轨迹
Once we go through this process,
走完这个流程后
we'll reach the murder scene in the end.
我们最后才去犯罪现场
So that you can imagine
这样你才能想象
where the culprit went and ended up running into the victim?
罪犯的行动路线和 在哪遇到了受害者？
-That's right. -I see.
-没错 -明白了
Anyway, how did you receive a report on Guro-gu's case?
你怎么得到了九老区案件的报告？
We asked for cooperation, so police stations nearby
我们请求协助附近的警察局
are checking similar cases.
正在调查相似的案件
We concluded that the Imyeong-dong case wasn't Gu Young-chun's doing.
我们推断任英洞案件不是具永春干的
Everyone has eyes on this case because of the park incident.
因为公园的事件大家都盯着这个案子
-They're cooperative. -I see.
-他们都很配合 -知道了
YONGCHEON VILLA
（龙泉公寓）
Compared to the cases from Geumcheon or Dongjak Stations,
金村警察局和铜雀警察局的案子相比
-it feels a bit different. -It is.
-这个案子感觉有点不一样 -确实
How so?
有什么不一样？
This isn't a residential area.
这里不是聚居区
This villa is secluded.
这个公寓很偏僻
-Let's go inside. -Shall we?
-我们进去吧 -可以吗？
The key was in the keyhole.
当时钥匙插在钥匙孔里
And her bag and wallet were on the floor.
她的提包和钱包落在了地上
-And the valuables were still in there? -Yes.
-值钱的东西还在包里吗？ -是的
Did he wait for the victim to go into the house?
他是要等受害者进屋了才动手吗？
What if she had family at home?
如果她家里有人怎么办？
Then his crime would've been exposed. Would he risk such danger?
这样他的罪行会暴露 他会冒这个险吗？
He's the type who shows his face,
他没有蒙面
so it's possible, although I don't understand it.
你说的可能是对的 尽管我不明白他为什么这么做
I think there might be another reason.
我觉得可能另有原因
Let's go back, then.
我们往回走
First off,
首先
he probably chased her up the stairs.
他可能追着女人往楼上跑
The victim puts the key in.
受害者把钥匙插进钥匙孔
She's about to go inside…
准备进屋
You startled me.
你吓着我了
I think he hesitated until the moment she went in.
我觉得杀人犯一直在犹豫 直到女人要进屋时才动手
The culprit seems aggressive, but he doesn't seem to be bold.
罪犯似乎很凶残 但是他胆子并不大
He's rather timid.
而是很胆小
All right.
好
Just as you said,
正如你说的那样
he would've hesitated until the last minute,
他可能一直在犹豫 直到最后关头
then found enough courage in that last moment.
才有了足够的勇气动手
Then what about showing himself
那么他为什么要将自己
under the bright light and stuff?
暴露在灯光下
He wasn't showing them his face.
他并不是想要别人看到他的脸
It's the other way around.
恰恰相反
He wanted to see the victim.
他想看到受害者
He wanted to check the victim's face before he kills a stranger?
他想在杀死一名陌生人之前 看清她的脸吗？
The moment he attacked them,
当杀人犯攻击受害者的时候
he was looking…
他想要看到
at the victim's expression.
受害者的表情
-Hey. -You're here.
-嘿 -你来了
This is it?
就这些吗？
-Please print these. -Okay.
-把这个打印出来 -好的
-Did you eat dinner? -Yes, I did.
-吃饭了吗？ -吃了
All right, then. Let's start with…
好了 我们开始吧
Let's hurry.
快点
-Let's see… -Hello.
-我们看一看 -你好
Oh, hello.
哦 你好
Take a look at this record.
看一下这个记录
It says right here…
它说道…
In that case, this is…
如果是这样的话…
I'll have to stay here until late at night.
我会在这待到很晚
Report back to me if anything comes up.
如果有什么新的情况 马上向我汇报
Sinheung 2-dong and Gocheong-dong.
在新兴二洞和高清洞的案件中
Both victims died in front of the door…
受害者都是死在了屋门口
with their key in the keyhole.
而且他们的钥匙都插在钥匙孔里
This shows the culprit hesitated
这表明罪犯一直在犹豫
until the very last moment.
直到最后关头才动手
If he's a timid guy,
如果他真是一个胆小的人
that explains why these victims were attacked near their house.
这也可以解释为什么受害者 都是在他们家附近遇害的
Right.
是的
The Gocheong-dong case broke out in April, so it must be before Pureumae Park.
高清洞的案件发生在4月 应该发生在苍鹰公园案件之前
Yes, there were too many cases reported to Dongjak Station,
是的 铜雀警察局接到的案子太多
so they recognized
因此他们先
the Pureumae Park case first.
调查了苍鹰公园案件
That means the culprit began to use a kitchen knife
这表示罪犯在4月份
starting in April.
就开始使用厨房用刀了
In that case,
如果是这样
the culprit changed the weapon to make sure he kills the victims,
罪犯更换了作案工具 是为了确保能杀死受害者
just as we predicted, right?
这和我们的猜测一样 对吧？
That's most probable.
很有可能是这样
Other than the Imyeong-dong case, other cases were injuries.
除了任英洞案件外 其他案件的受害者只是受伤
These results probably made the culprit more anxious.
这个结果可能让罪犯感到焦急
And he has evolved.
因此他改进了作案手法
He might have studied the ways just as Gu Young-chun did.
他可能像具永春一样研究了杀人方式
He studied?
他做了研究？
These people study a lot to kill.
这些人研究了很多杀人的手法
That's why he made the steel hammer himself.
这也是罪犯自制了钢锤的原因
These psychos are beyond my imagination.
这些变态杀人犯真是超出了我的想象
Gocheong-dong is in Guro-gu too.
高清洞也在九老区
The cases are mostly in the southwestern area.
这些案件大多数发生在西南部
Do you really think he's behind the Imyeong-dong case?
你认为任英洞案件是他干的吗？
We thought about it for a long time.
我们也想了很久
But look at the subway line. Line one.
你看一下地铁线路 一号线
Like this.
这里
Most of these areas are near line number one.
大多数案发地点在一号线附近
Sometimes line number two.
有一些案发地点在二号线附近
We thought the area was within the culprit's usual reach.
我们认为这是罪犯很熟悉的活动范围
He might be someone who lives around line one.
他可能是居住在一号线附近的居民
Gu Young-chun traveled
具永春通过来回转悠
back and forth to confuse us.
来迷惑我们
He also claimed he took the subway,
具永春还声称搭乘过地铁
but this guy doesn't seem to be that meticulous.
但是这个家伙心思似乎没有那么缜密
The cases in the southwestern area are
在西南部的这些案件里
in different jurisdictions,
发生在不同的管辖地
but they are all within walking distance.
但是这些地方都在步行的范围内
Precisely.
的确如此
Also, he does not look for his victims before he acts.
而且他并不会确定犯罪对象
He went out at dawn or late at night,
他通常在凌晨和半夜出门
when there aren't many people to find a target,
趁人不多的时候寻找独行女性
then followed and attacked them ruthlessly.
然后跟踪 无情地杀死她们
So we're looking for a psycho who's lurking around the Southwestern area
也就是说 我们正在寻找一个潜伏在西南部
with a knife in his hand.
手里拿着刀的变态杀人犯
You're right. That's him.
没错 就是这样
What if he fails to find a victim?
如果他没有物色到受害者怎么办？
I'm sure there are days he fails.
我相信他也会有扑空的时候
If such days continue…
如果持续这样的话
As you can see, he changed his weapon.
你也看到了 他会更换作案工具
Then he'll change his MO, just as Gu Young-chun did.
更换作案手法 就像具永春一样
He changed his weapon from a camping knife to a kitchen knife.
他将作案工具由野营小刀 换成了厨房用刀
What will it be next?
下一次会换成什么呢？
PROFILING (CRIME ANALYSIS) REPORT
（犯罪侧写报告）
Will it be a steel hammer like Gu Young-chun?
会和具永春一样使用钢锤吗？
GOCHEONG-DONG MURDER CASE
（高清洞谋杀案）
His MO evolved by studying his crimes.
他的作案手法是通过 研究他的犯罪行为发展而来的
He's timid.
在人流量不多的时候
He hides in an alley and looks for a victim.
躲在小巷子里物色受害者的胆小性格
But he's aggressive enough
但是当他攻击受害者时
to watch his victim in pain as he attacks them.
会观察受害者痛苦的表情 表现出凶残的一面
What's next?
下一次会是什么呢？
Where will he be?
他会到哪去？
How far will he go?
他会去多远的地方？
Inspector Song?
宋警卫？
You're here.
你在这啊
I heard you were at the prosecution.
我听说你在检察厅
We got done much faster than I expected,
我们提前完成了工作
so I stopped by.
因此顺便过来看一下
I read the case file
我看了关于高清洞
on the Gocheong-dong case.
案件的档案
And this is the profile report.
这是犯罪侧写报告
I'll share this with the SCS tomorrow.
明天我会和机搜队一起看这份报告
"The culprit is introverted because he lacks the ability
因缺乏社会交往能力
to make social connections."
而导致的内向性格
I remember you made a similar analysis
我记得你在几年前
with Cho Hyun-gil a few years ago.
为赵贤吉也做了相似的分析
-Is that correct? -Yes.
-是不是？ -是
Back then, you said that he chose young kids because
当时 你说赵贤吉选择儿童实施性侵
they wouldn't be repelled by him, and then he sexually assaulted them.
是因为儿童对他不反感
That was the reason you gave us to support your claim.
这是当时你为我们提供的依据
What about this one?
这个人又是什么情况呢？
It's similar.
很相似
I concluded that he didn't have the social skills
我推断他没有引诱受害者的
or the guts to lure his victims.
社交能力和胆量
That sounds plausible.
这听起来很合理
After all, he followed his victims at the scene.
罪犯在犯罪现场都是跟踪作案
Right.
是的
But what worries me is that
但是让我担心的是
his MO is progressing.
他正在改进作案手法
It's progressing.
改进
We need to increase the range of similar cases we investigate.
我们需要扩大相似案件的调查范围
Right. But there seem to be
是的 但是这里面
a lot of hypotheticals again.
有很多不清楚的地方
It will be difficult to make them understand
很难让高层明白
on what ground you want
你是基于什么理由
the investigation to be expanded to.
想要扩大调查范围到什么程度
The more we hesitate and delay it,
我们越是拖延 越是犹豫不决
the more victims there will be.
受害者就会越多
The Special Crime Squad wants to catch the culprit
机搜队也和你们一样
as soon as possible too.
想要抓到犯人
Are you still drawing a line between our teams
现在不断地有无辜的人死去
even when innocent people are dying?
还要把分析组和机搜队分那么清楚？
That's not what I was doing.
我不是这个意思
It's likely that he will move on to breaking and entering or arson.
入室盗窃纵火的可能性是很小的
-Arson? -Serial killers.
-纵火？ -连环杀人犯
They enjoy arson.
通常喜欢纵火
It's an easy way to satisfy their urges.
这是满足他们心理的最简单的方式
And one more thing.
还有一点
Being timid during the act
在作案时谨小慎微
is his unique factor.
是他们的独特特征
GOCHEONG-DONG MURDER CASE
（高清洞谋杀案）
DATE, TIME, AND LOCATION
（案件发生日期、场所）
The murder case took place in April in a low-rise villa in Gocheong-dong.
这宗谋杀案发生在4月份 案发地点在高清洞的一栋低层公寓
The victim was attacked in front of the door
受害者在家门口遇到了袭击
with the key in the keyhole.
钥匙还插在钥匙孔中
This incident resembles
这个案件和2月份发生在
the one that took place in the villa in Sinheung 2-dong in February.
新兴二洞的一栋公寓的案件非常相似
We noticed many factors which indicated that
很多线索表明
these incidents were carried out
这些案件是由
by the culprit of the Southwest Murder Case.
西南谋杀案的罪犯实施的
There's so much.
挺多的
Inspector Song is focusing on the progression of his crimes.
宋警卫正在分析他的犯罪
He speculated the culprit might break in and commit arson.
他预测罪犯会入室行凶和纵火
Well, I get why the culprit might start breaking into houses.
哦 罪犯入室行凶我能理解
But arson too?
但是为什么要纵火呢？
Right.
是啊
Gu Young-chun only set the house on fire to remove his traces.
具永春纵火只是为了消除犯罪痕迹
I'm not so sure if it's right to put serial killers and arsonists
连环杀人犯和纵火犯
in the same group.
能归为一类吗？
He said serial killers are used to committing arson.
他说连环杀人犯通常会纵火
But still. This is too big of a range.
但是这个调查范围也太广了吧
Right.
是啊
Then we have to investigate all the violent crimes.
那样就需要调查所有的暴力犯罪
This is Yoon Tae-gu.
我是首尔厅的尹泰九
Please share any break-in and arson cases with us.
请向我们提供入室行凶 和纵火的案件资料
But only the ones where valuables or money weren't taken.
只提供财物未遭到盗窃的案件资料
Hold on.
等一下
Please include cases as long as the amount isn't big.
请同时提供被盗金额不大的案件资料
What are these?
这些是什么呀？
He keeps changing his weapon.
他一直在换作案工具
A camping to a kitchen knife.
从野营小刀到厨房用刀
I'm sure he'll change it again.
我相信他会再次更换作案工具
Put them away after you study them.
你们研究完了之后收起来
They are just tools.
这些都只是工具
But they look creepy in this office.
但是放在办公室里感觉很恐怖
What's wrong? What was that?
怎么了？你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Becoming him.
成为他
Becoming him?
成为他？
I'm trying to become the culprit.
我在尝试成为罪犯
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
The police decided to reform their system
警方决定进行制度改革
in order to handle criminal cases
是为了处理像近期连环杀人案一样的
that target random people just like the recent serial murder case.
任意目标犯罪案件
The police agency
警察厅
set up an investigation support center to prepare for the violent crimes
设立了调查支持中心 以应对暴力犯罪
and decided to reform the Special Crime Squads
并决定将机搜队改编
into Wide-Area Investigation Squads.
为广域调查队
On a day like today,
像今天这样的日子
you ought to drink beer and soju together, Gil-pyo.
许队长应该喝点啤酒加烧酒才是
Here you go.
来吧
Enough.
够了
What do you mean? Here.
说啥呢？来
-Okay. Cheers. -All right.
-好 干杯 -好的
-Good job. -Okay.
-辛苦了 -好
The tripe here is great.
这家的牛百叶特别好吃
Superintendent Heo Gil-pyo of Gyeonggi Provincial Police Agency.
京畿道警察厅许队长
Too bad that you won't get to see me now.
你以后就见不到我了 太糟了
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呀？
I'm finally going to have good bowel movements.
我以后终于可以逍遥了
When you go to Gyeonggi, shave.
去京畿道之前刮一下胡子
Try to look clean.
要收拾得干干净净的
It's only a 50 minute drive from here.
京畿道到这里只要50分钟的车程
You can visit us anytime, right?
你会随时来看我们的 对吗？
No, it takes longer with the traffic jam.
不会 如果遇上塞车 过来要花很长时间
There are a lot more cars after the World Cup.
世界杯赛之后 车就变多了
The outer ring road is all set up now.
现在有外环线了
It's hard to visit when you go somewhere else. You'll know soon.
去了别的地方后就很难再见了 你们很快会知道的
Please don't forget us when you transfer.
转部门后不要忘了我们
Of course, not.
当然不会忘
-Exactly. Gil-pyo won't forget us. -Of course.
-没错 许队长不会忘记我们的 -当然
Good work.
辛苦了
By the way, you lost a lot of weight, Inspector Song.
对了 宋警卫 你瘦了
-Me? -Yes.
-我吗？ -对啊
I don't have an appetite these days.
我这几天吃饭没有胃口
-Goodness. -Here. Eat a lot.
-天啊 -来 多吃点
I know you and Young-soo are insanely busy.
我知道你和荣秀非常忙
I don't think you're in any position to worry about others.
你不要为别人操心了
You know what?
听我说
I'm sure Superintendent Heo and Captain Kook will do a great job.
我相信许队长和国组长都会干得很好
He's Chief Kook now.
他现在是国队长了
I don't like changes.
我不喜欢你们改口
Just call me Captain Kook.
还是叫我国组长吧
How could we, Chief Kook?
这怎么能行呢 国队长？
Come on.
得了
It sounds like Chief Cook. I don't like it.
听起来像厨师 我不喜欢
I'll get going first.
我先走了
-Are you going to the scene? -Yes.
-你要去犯罪现场吗？ -是的
If you have work to do, don't feel bad. You can go.
如果你有工作要忙 没有关系 去吧
-Let me go with you. -No. I'll go alone. Stay here.
-让我和你一起去吧 -不用 我一个人去 你留下吧
-I'm sorry. Please excuse me. -Sure.
-对不起 抱歉 -没事
-I'll get going. -Okay.
-我走了 -好的
Bye.
再见
Who are you?
你是谁？
What are you doing here?
你在干什么？
Right.
哦
I'm sorry. I'm a police officer.
对不起 我是一名警察
During the resident meeting, we talked about
在开业主会的时候 我们谈到了
a strange man lurking around the building.
有一个陌生人潜伏在楼房周围
Can't you be considerate of the people who live here?
你考虑过这里的居民的感受吗？
-Sorry. -Don't stand there.
-对不起 -请不要站在这里
If you're done, get out!
如果你已经忙完了 请出去
Okay.
好的
Sorry, my foot.
什么对不起
So what if you're a cop?
警察有什么了不起
Beat it!
赶紧走
YONGCHEON VILLA
（龙泉公寓）
-Bye.
-再见
-Goodbye. -See you.
-一会见
-Sir, there's a taxi. -Bye.
-出租车来了 -再见
-Okay. Get me a taxi. -The taxi.
-好 叫辆出租车 -出租车
-Yeonhui-dong! -Over here. Take the taxi.
-延禧洞 -过来 出租车
-Bye. -Chief Kook.
-再见 -国队长
Bye. See you tomorrow.
再见 明天见
SONG HA-YOUNG
（宋霞永）
Who is it?
谁啊？
Ma'am, it's Kook Young-soo.
你好 女士 我是国荣秀
Sir.
组长
Hey.
哦
You're just getting home.
你刚到家啊
Your mother needs to sleep.
你的母亲需要休息
So I'll leave after I nag on you for a bit.
我和你聊一会就走
-Please sit. -Okay.
-请坐 -好的
It is good to be focused on work,
虽然专注于工作是好事
but it is important to separate work from home.
但是把工作和家庭分开也很重要
I know.
我知道
But it's not easy.
但是很难
I live alone, so it's a different story.
我一个人生活 和你不一样
But you live with your mother.
但是你和你的母亲生活在一起
If you leave these case files wide open…
如果这些档案让她看到了
she'll be worried.
她会担心的
She has a good understanding of what I do.
她非常理解我的工作
That's different from how concerned she must be as a mother.
理解你的工作不代表她不心疼你
You need to learn to pay attention
你要学会关心
to the people around you too.
你身边的人
Thank you for the advice…
感谢你的建议
and also for your nagging.
还有唠叨
But it comes off as being cheesy at this time of night.
但是这么晚过来 让我有点受宠若惊
Good point.
有道理
I should get going before you kick me out.
在你赶我出门之前我得先走了
-Captain Kook. -Tidy up a little.
-国组长 -把屋子收拾一下
I'm off.
我走了
I'll try.
我会努力做到的
Of course, you should.
当然 你应该这样
We're in for a long haul.
但我们要的是长远的努力
Right.
是的
-Bye.
-再见
-Get home safely. -Okay.
-一路平安 -好的
Thirteen murders that took place in the metropolitan area
在过去两年发生在市区的
in the past two years still remain unsolved.
十三宗谋杀案还没有被侦破
At this rate, they'll most likely become cold cases
照这样下去 这些案子将会成为悬案
where the killers remain uncaught.
杀人犯仍然会逍遥法外
The murders of the three women in southwestern Seoul,
从四月份开始发生在首尔西南部的
which began in April, still remain unsolved.
三宗女性谋杀案仍然没有被侦破
The police have announced
警方宣布
they'd investigate missing person cases,
他们会调查失踪人口案件
but the public trust on them is low.
但是公众对警方缺乏信任
Since there is no evidence of sexual assault,
由于没有性侵的证据
the police are investigating the incidents
于是警方将案件当作
as simple mugging cases or attacks caused by resentment.
单纯的抢劫或仇杀案件处理
It seems the culprit usually uses subway line one.
罪犯似乎通常乘坐一号线
Most of the Southwest Cases
大多数西南部案件
took place late at night or after midnight.
都发生在午夜前后
If he fails to find a target…
如果他没有物色到犯罪目标
He takes the risk of attacking right before his victim opens the door,
他会冒险在受害者开门之前发动袭击
because he's obsessed with murder.
他已经沉迷于杀人了
-Why are you so late? -You're still up?
-为什么这么晚？ -你还没睡吗？
I was so worried. Come on in.
我好担心你 进来吧
So he won't give up
他永远不会停止犯罪
until his day is over.
直到他的末日来临
MIBUN-DONG, GUNPO
（美分洞 军浦）
Would you like a bottle of juice?
你想喝瓶果汁吗？
Ma'am.
女士
Anybody around?
有人吗？
There's a woman collapsed on the ground.
有个女人倒在了地上 有人吗？
Hello, you've reached
你好 这里是
the Behavioral Analysis Team.
犯罪行为分析组
Inspector Song Ha-young?
找宋霞永吗？
What is it about?
什么事？
Gunpo Police Station?
军浦警察局？
I see. Fax us the details. I'll pass it along.
知道了 把资料传真给我们 我会转给他
Gunpo? Is it about a new case?
军浦？是新案子吗？
Yes, they think it could be a serial case.
是的 他们认为有可能是连环案件
They want us to take a look.
他希望我们去看一下
The victims in both cases
在这两宗案件中
were stabbed in the stomach with the same weapon.
受害者都是腹部被同样的凶器刺中
Near Geumyang Station and Gunpo Station,
两宗案件分别发生在 金阳站和军浦站附近
both on subway line one.
都属于一号线
What kind of weapon?
什么样的凶器？
The autopsy says a fruit knife.
尸检报告说是水果刀
Those blades are less than 10cm long.
刀刃不到10厘米长
Just like camping knives.
野营用刀概率要大一些
And no money or valuables were stolen?
而且没有钱财被盗
But this is the most important.
但这是很重要的线索
FACIAL COMPOSITE RESULT
（面部合成结果）
Looks a lot like the culprit in the Southwest Cases.
看起来很像西南部案件的罪犯
The cases in Gunpo took place at around 6 a.m. and 5:40 a.m.
军浦案件的案发时间 大概是早上5点40分至6点
There was a huge risk of being seen, but he took the risk regardless.
有罪行暴露的巨大风险 但他毫不顾及风险
A while ago, you mentioned something about timid aggression.
之前 你曾经说过罪犯比较胆小
Is that relevant here?
这是不是有点说不通啊？
Yes. He's timid, so he prefers to do it when people aren't out and around,
是的 罪犯是胆小的 因此他会选择在没有人的时候动手
but he did this in the morning.
但是这次罪犯在早上作案
It shows us he's willing to take a risk
证明他具有为了杀人而冒险的
just to kill.
极强攻击性
He was probably on his way home after failing to find a suitable victim
也许罪犯没有物色到合适的受害者 这时正在回家的路上
when he ran into the juice lady near his home.
然后在他家附近遇到了卖果汁的女士
In other words, he was determined to kill.
也就是说 他下定决心要杀人
Yes, at all costs.
是的 无论任何代价
Why don't you call Gil-pyo and ask him
不如打电话给许队长
to share the reports on the cases occurred in Gyeonggi?
让他向我们提供 京畿道发生的案件的报告
Then we'd be able to find more similar cases.
这样我们可以发现更多类似的案件
That's no problem at all,
完全没有问题
but there will be a ton of reports.
但是会有一大堆报告
We'll start with the ones that took place this year.
我们可以从今年发生的案件开始查
We'll give it a shot.
我们先试一试吧
CAMPING KNIFE NORTHERN AREA
（野营刀 北部）
ARSON BREAK-INS
（纵火 入室案）
PRINTING
（打印）
Put it here.
放在这里
Have you checked it yet?
你查看过了吗？
-Here. -I was reading that.
-这里 -我正在看
It's never-ending.
永远都完成不了啊
-Anyang. -I'll put the northern district ones here.
-安阳 -我把北区的报告放在这里
Do we have the ones from the southern district too?
我们有南区的报告吗？
DAILY CASE REPORT
（每日案件报告）
Let's have lunch.
我们去吃午饭吧
-Sounds good. -Let's go.
-好主意 -走吧
Let's go eat something.
我们去吃点东西
You guys go ahead. I'm not hungry.
你们先去吧 我不饿
My goodness.
天啊
DAILY CASE REPORT
（每日案件报告）
-Ha-young. -Yes?
-霞永 -嗯？
What's that?
这是什么？
Oh, this. It's from Forensics.
这个啊 这是从鉴定组拿的
Why are you putting it in your drawer?
你为什么把它放在抽屉里？
I'll return it later with the other things.
晚点我会和其他东西一起还回去
-Hand it over. -Sorry?
-交出来 -什么？
Hand it over. I'll go return it.
交出来 我来还回去
-I'll return it later. -Song Ha-young!
-我等一下还回去 -宋霞永
This is not the first time we got a call regarding this.
这不是我们第一次接到这样的报案了
My apologies. This won't happen again.
对不起 这种事情不会再发生了
-Please be more cautious from now on. -Of course. I'm sorry.
-以后请多加注意 -当然 对不起
Thank you for your hard work. We'll get going.
辛苦了 我们走了
-Thank you. -Yes, I'll leave you to it then.
-这么忙还给你们添麻烦 辛苦了 -好的 这里交给你了
Okay.
好的
-Take care. -Thanks, you too.
-保重 -谢谢 你们也保重
Let's get something to drink.
我们一起去喝点吧
For the first time, I'm starting to wonder if I made the right choice.
我这是第一次 开始怀疑我所做的是否正确
I was merely trying…
我只是想试图
to put myself in the culprit's shoes.
走进罪犯的内心世界
It's better not to know if you have to wield a weapon just like them.
如果你非得像罪犯一样挥舞着凶器 你最好别干了
I was not trying to harm anyone.
我并不想伤害任何人
But you were a threat.
但是你威胁到别人了
I know it is important to think in their shoes.
我知道揣摩罪犯的心理很重要
But this method is too dangerous.
但是这个方法太危险了
Look at you.
看看你自己
Just take a look at yourself right now.
看一看自己什么样
Looking into those bastards' minds? It's all good.
走进那些混蛋的内心世界 这都没有错
But before that…
但是这样做之前
Take care of yourself first. Please.
先照顾好自己 拜托了
Whenever I think about them roaming around
每当我想到他们在到处游荡
and killing innocent people…
杀死无辜的人
At night these days,
最近在夜里
I'm reminded of the victims' faces.
我经常想起受害者的模样
So this is the method you chose?
这就是你选择的方法？
Do you need to murder someone to catch him?
你是不是需要杀个人才能抓住罪犯？
You seem very unstable right now.
现在你的情绪很不稳定
I just want to catch them. That's all.
我只是想抓住罪犯 仅此而已
I feel like that responsibility
我感觉你的责任感
is weighing you down too much.
把你压的死死的
Ever since your interview with Gu Young-chun,
在你审问了具永春以后
you became more impatient.
你变得更加没有耐心了
But Ha-young.
但是霞永
You have endured everything so well up until now.
经历这么多事情 你能一路走下来也很难得
It's surprising.
非常棒
But we're in for a long haul.
但我们要的是长远的努力
Take some days off.
休几天假吧
-I can manage. -Ha-young.
-我没事 -霞永
I'm sorry for this.
对此我很抱歉
This will never happen again. Let's go.
这种事情再也不会发生了 我们走吧
So this is the method you chose?
这就是你选择的方法？
Do you need to murder someone to catch him?
你是不是需要杀个人才能抓住罪犯？
With crimes happening one after another,
随着犯罪接连发生
anxiety is starting to spread among the people.
恐慌开始在人群中蔓延
The people think that the police are unreliable.
人们认为警察是靠不住的
Hello?
你好
Can you come pick me up later?
你等会能接我吗？
In one town in Seoul, residents have been taking turns
在首尔的一个小镇 居民开始在夜间的公园
patrolling the dark and desolate streets at night.
和人流少的街道轮流巡逻
Only the people's troubles and burdens have increased
由于社会混乱和不稳定的治安
due to our society's troubling times and unstable public order.
人们的烦恼和负担与日俱增
MARCH, 2006
（2006年3月）
MOGU-DONG, GWANAK-GU
（毛九洞 冠岳区）
A fire broke out at a house in Mogu-dong, Gwanak-gu at dawn today.
今天早上冠岳区毛九洞的 一处房屋出现火灾
The parents who slept in the master bedroom evacuated.
睡在主卧的一对夫妇成功逃生
But the daughter who was sleeping in the other room was found dead.
但是睡在另外一个房间 的女儿被发现已身亡
The police are taking note of the fact that there are traces
警方发现了受害者
of the victim being bludgeoned in the head multiple times.
头部曾遭到反复击打的痕迹
They're considering the possibility
警方认为罪犯纵火
that the culprit started the fire to cover up the murder.
有可能是为了掩盖谋杀的事实
The footsteps from the balcony headed for the small room first.
脚印显示罪犯先从阳台走到了小房间
CRIME SCENE STEPPING PLATES
（犯罪现场通行板）
He wasn't after the valuables.
他并不是为了盗窃财物
Right, since cash or expensive jewelry are usually kept in the master bedroom.
是的 现金和贵重珠宝一般放在主卧
-You're here. -Hello.
-你来了 -你好
I think it started from here.
罪犯是从这里进来的
He stood here and hesitated.
他站在这里犹豫了一会
What was he hesitating about?
他在犹豫什么呢？
If it were me…
如果是我的话…
Hey, what do you mean, "If it were me"?
你说“如果是我的话”是什么意思？
If I were the culprit, I would have headed towards the small room first.
如果我是罪犯 我会先去小房间
Timid aggression.
胆小攻击型
It's the unique trait from the Southwest Case.
这是西南部案件的独特特征
Do you think it's the same guy?
你认为是同一个罪犯吗？
Yes.
是的
CRIME SCENE STEPPING PLATES
（犯罪现场通行板）
Usually, there are children
通常小孩
in the smaller rooms.
睡在小房间里
Yes, that's true.
是的 没错
Ha-young.
霞永
Just as Inspector Song speculated,
和宋警卫预测的一样
he broke in and it led to arson.
罪犯入室行凶并纵火
Chief Kook.
国股长
I received a call from Gwanak Station asking for your team.
冠岳警察局打电话给我 请求你们组协助他们
-They called you first? -Yes, they did.
-他们直接打电话给你吗？ -是的
Those guys are at a loss,
这些人找不到头绪
so I think they are curious.
他们一定很好奇
Go with Inspector Song
你和宋警卫一起去
and brief them on the profiling analysis you made.
向他们介绍你们的犯罪侧写分析
I wonder if they'll even listen.
我想知道他们是否会听
I'm not sure.
我也不知道
They may not be welcoming since it's their first time.
刚开始可能会有点排斥
I'm sure you'll do fine.
相信我 你会干好的
-Okay, we'll do our best. -All right.
-好的 我会尽力 -好的
SEOUL GWANAK POLICE STATION
（首尔冠岳警察局）
The culprit for Mogu-dong and Southwest Cases
毛九洞和西南部案件的罪犯
is the same guy.
应该是同一个人
And he used different weapons and used them repeatedly.
罪犯重复使用了不同的凶器
On top of that, he's used to walking and running.
而且他经常步行和跑步
He walked to the scenes, so he's probably in sneakers.
罪犯是步行到犯罪现场的 因此他可能穿的是运动鞋
He probably hid his weapon somewhere.
他有可能将凶器藏在了某处
How do you know?
你是怎么知道的？
It depends on how you attack someone,
这要取决于袭击受害者的方式
but weapons that can kill are big and sharp,
能够杀死人的凶器通常很大 很锋利
so they're noticeable.
因此很显眼
He couldn't have carried it around.
罪犯不可能随身携带
But there is a high chance that he carries around
但是他很可能会随身携带小型凶器
small weapons like a camping knife.
比如野营小刀
Also, his murder attempts weren't successful every time,
而且他的谋杀企图不是每次都会成功
so we must look into small cases of violence
我们必须调查发生在
that break out at night.
夜晚的轻微暴力案件
Who does he think he is to give us a sermon? Right?
他以为他自己很帅？在这说教？
Right.
是啊
He was in the newspaper too, so let's hear him out first.
他可是上过报纸的 让我们听一听他说的吧
The culprit is probably around 35 years old.
罪犯的年龄在35岁左右
Is he a shaman or what?
他是不是巫师呀？
-Exactly. -Tell me about it.
-确实 -告诉我们吧
Why is he in his mid-thirties?
他为什么是35岁左右？
Behavioral Analysis Team
犯罪行为分析组
turned over 1,000 violent crimes and cases of violence into data.
分析了超过1000宗暴力犯罪和案件
Hey, wait.
等一下
Over 1,000 cases?
超过1000宗案件？
And we've interviewed over 200 criminals.
我们采访了超过200名罪犯
-What? -Over 200?
-什么？ -超过200
We used this data to analyze the random killings,
我们使用这些数据分析国内随机谋杀
and most of the culprits were between 33 and 37 years old.
大多数罪犯的年龄在33岁至37岁之间
So he isn't just a shaman.
看来他不只是一个巫师
In order for his anger to blow up,
罪犯应该至少有30岁了
he should at least be in his thirties to have enough social provocation.
这样才会对社会有足够的怨恨 想要发泄他的怒火
Don't people in their twenties blow up in anger more often?
20多岁的年轻人不是更容易发火吗？
-Young people are scarier. -Right.
-年轻人更可怕 -是啊
You're right.
你说得对
People in their twenties tend to be more impulsive.
20多岁的年轻人更容易冲动
However, no, perhaps that's why their crimes are mostly random,
这也是为什么他们的犯罪多是 临时起意的原因
without a plan or bringing changes into their MO.
没有计划 犯罪手法也没有变化
The culprit lacks social skills.
罪犯缺乏社交能力
So if you talk to him,
如果你和他交谈
there is a high possibility that he'll avoid your eyes.
他很可能会避开你的目光
-Get it out there. -Yes, hurry.
-出发 -好的 快点
-Do we look into those cases? -Yes.
-我们要查看这些案子吗？ -是的
All cases. Culprits must be in their thirties.
所有案子 罪犯应该是30多岁
Excuse me.
对不起
-Excuse me, sir. -What is it?
-对不起 先生 -什么事？
We're from Gwanak Police Station.
我们是冠岳警察局的
I'm sorry to ask, but could you take your glasses off?
不好意思 您能不能摘掉眼镜？
We're from Gwanak Police Station. Are you Kim In-kyu, 38 years old?
您是金寅奎 今年38岁 对吗？
That's me.
是的
By any chance, have you seen a man who looks like this around here?
您是否在附近看见过 模样和这个图片相似的男人
Have you seen a man who looks like this?
您是否见过和这个图片相似的男人？
I haven't.
没见过
SINHEUNG 6-DONG, YEONGDEUNGPO-GU
（新兴二洞 永登浦区）
What? Who are you?
干什么？你是谁？
What?
干什么？
Hey, let go of me!
嘿 放开我
You bastard!
你这个混蛋
Over here.
在那边
We're from Sinheung Precinct. Who called it in?
我们是新兴派出所的 谁报的案？
It was me.
是我
This bastard. He's a robber.
这个混蛋是个强盗
My son almost died.
我的儿子差点死了
What kind of an robber carries such a heavy weapon?
哪个强盗会带这么重的武器啊？
-So stupid. -Tell me about it.
-太愚蠢了 -告诉我们吧
Isn't that too heavy for you?
是不是拿着很重啊？
You should go out and get a job.
你应该去找个工作
People get paid a lot for day labor these days.
现在干体力活都能挣很多钱
Exactly.
对啊
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATIONS DIVISION BEHAVIORAL ANALYSIS TEAM
（科学调查股 犯罪行为分析组）
Inspector Song.
宋警卫
What is this?
这是什么？
NAM KI-TAE
（南基泰）
It's from Yeongdeungpo Police Station.
这是来自永登浦警察局的报告
SPOTTED RELEVANCE WITH SOUTHWEST CASE
（发现和西南部案件有关）
YEONGDEUNGPO POLICE STATION
（永登浦警察局）
-What's wrong with you? -We caught the man!
-怎么回事？ -人是我们抓的
-That's nonsense! -What are you saying?
-岂有此理 -你说什么？
Hello, one second.
对不起 等一下
One second.
等一下
All right, now.
好了
Everyone, look here.
大家好
Superintendent Baek.
我是白科长
I'm Superintendent Baek Jun-sik of Seoul Agency.
首尔警察厅的白科长
-Yes. -Hello.
-好的 -你好
I understand that you are all dying to interrogate this guy.
我明白你们都想审问这个罪犯
But first, this profiler, Inspector Song Ha-young,
但是首先 这位犯罪侧写师 也就是宋霞永警卫
will have a talk with the suspect.
要和嫌疑犯聊一下
After that, we'll hear out what Inspector Song has to say.
我们之后听一下宋警卫的发言再调查
And then we'll interrogate him.
然后我们再审问罪犯
-But he's not the one who-- -I get it. I know.
-但是他并不是… -我明白
We know that Yeongdeungpo got him first. We'll give you enough time in order.
我知道是永登浦警察局抓到人的 会给你们足够时间审问
What?
怎么回事？
Do you know me?
你认识我吗？
HOW THE PROFILER CAUGHT GU YOUNG-CHUN
（犯罪侧写师如何抓住具永春？）
IT'S THAT CAREER YOU SAW IN THE SILENCE OF THE LAMBS
（电影《沉默的羔羊》中的职业）
Gu Young-chun.
具永春
You're the guy who caught him.
是你抓住了他
He's the one we've been looking for.
他就是我们要找的人
STAY TUNED FOR THE EPILOGUE
（稍后播出后记）
PROFILING (CRIME ANALYSIS) REPORT
（犯罪侧写报告）
HOW THE PROFILER CAUGHT GU YOUNG-CHUN
（犯罪侧写师如何抓住具永春？）
GU YOUNG-CHUN PSYCHOLOGICAL ANALYSIS
（具永春心理分析）
CHILDHOOD, CRIME PREPARATION
（成长过程 犯罪准备）
I have a question.
我有一个问题
The results on his childhood and his emotional and cognitive thinking
正如在采访报告中看到的
are all shared by criminals
具永春的童年经历 情绪和认知能力
as we can see in our interview reports.
是许多罪犯的共同特征
Then if we put these characteristics together,
如果我们将这些特征结合
can we predict someone who will be a monster in the future?
是否能预测某人会在未来成为恶魔？
That's the most troubling area.
这是一个难题
For example, arson and animal abuse
例如 到了某个年纪之后
that are spotted after a certain age are considered as signs
仍然有纵火和虐待动物的行为
of a potential serial killer.
被认为是成为连环杀人犯的预兆
Gu Young-chun's childhood does match with the theory,
具永春的童年经历不符合这个理论
but I'm not sure if we should include this.
我不知道要不要将他的经历包括进去
You're right.
说得对
People who had a bad childhood
有过悲惨童年的人
don't all become criminals.
不一定都会变成罪犯
Some people end up becoming stronger.
有些人变得更强大了
I went through a lot because we were dirt-poor.
我从小贫困 吃了很多苦
But I grew up into a detective.
但是最后成长为了一名侦探
And I grew up with a single mother.
我是在很平凡的家庭长大的
Do you think monsters are born or made?
你认为恶魔是天生的还是后天的？
I'm not sure.
我不知道
If such lives are decided from the moment they're born,
如果他们的命运从出生那刻就决定了
it just seems too unfair and cruel.
那是多么地不公和残酷啊
Life is always unfair.
生活本来就是不公平的
At times, when I'm sitting with criminals,
有时候 当我面对罪犯时
I want to believe that people are born evil.
我宁愿相信人天生是邪恶的
"He must have always been that evil. There's no way he was once good."
他一定一直都那么坏 他不可能曾经善良过
And if such people are made,
如果邪恶是后天形成的
our world is hopeless.
这也太令人绝望了
The world that created the monster
让人变成恶魔的世界
must take responsibility too.
必须也要承担责任
Right.
对啊
I wonder what childhood they had…
到底是什么样的环境
to become such monsters.
才会让他们变成那样的恶魔？
I want to believe that people are born evil,
我相信性恶论
but a bigger part of me wants to believe people are born good.
但是我心里更想相信人性本善
"One's perception of others determines
人是性本善还是性本恶
whether people are inherently good or evil."
取决于自己如何看待他人
That's what I heard.
这是我听到的一句话
Then it means I haven't given up hope on people, right?
也就是说我没有对人类失去希望吗？
What about you?
你是怎么想的？
I don't think it matters how we're born.
我觉得出生并不重要
It's important to remember
重要的是要记住
that decisions are made by us, not by other people.
别人不能决定什么 一切取决于我们自己
Right. Whether or not our world has monsters,
是的 不管恶魔是不是天生的
it's important to remember that anyone can become one.
重要的是要记住 任何人都可能成为恶魔
It's been four years since our team was formed.
分析组已经成立四年了
A part of me is concerned.
我有点担心你
Don't go in too deep.
不要陷得太深
If you do,
如果你陷得太深
you might fall into that hole.
你会掉进深渊里
I'm not here to interrogate you.
我不是来审问你的
I here to speak with you.
我是来和你聊天的
There was no luminol reaction.
听说没有鲁米诺反应
We need to find the victim's DNA.
我们需要找到受害者的DNA
We won't be forced to release him, right?
我们不会被迫放了他吧？
This punk is no joke.
这混蛋不一般啊
Nam Ki-tae also gave his all to his murders.
南基泰为了杀人不择手段
Do you want to hear my story?
你想听我的故事吗？
I couldn't share this with anyone, so I was really frustrated.
我不能告诉任何人 因此我很郁闷
"He who fights with monsters
和恶魔缠斗的人
should look to it that he himself does not become a monster."
要小心自己不要成为恶魔
There's no need for you to bear it all yourself.
你没有必要一个人去承受
I wouldn't have even started if I was going to avoid it.
如果我想要回避 我就不会开始了